Cara Adelson

Email: cara.adelson@gmail.com | Phone: 315-558-3822 | Denver, CO 80218 LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/cara-adelson | GitHub: https://github.com/cgad

Website: https://cgad.dev

SUMMARY

Analytical and independent Full Stack Web Developer able to build a sophisticated website with full database backend all the way from mockup to rollout. Adept at working with diverse teams to implement projects. Strive for maximum efficiency and solution-orientation in code, workflow, and communication. Current role as TA shows enthusiasm for coding and mastery of material. Prior start-up and project management experience. Innate attitude and workflow habits align with Agile core values and behavioral skills like communication and performance effectiveness. Motivated by desire to learn. Cognitively aware.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, REST APIs, external API integration, React, SQL + NoSQL, Express, Node, NPM, Command Line, Linux/Unix, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, SCSS, Sass, Version Control, Unit Testing + more.

PROJECTS include

- Register as a user, create a profile, write posts to the feed, comment on posts, delete account.
- User authentication on private routes, error handling on form components.
- MERN, React, Redux, Passport, JWT.

- View search history, delete entries.
- Results presented in terms of greenhouse gas emission equivalents such as number of cars off the road for a day.
- MERN, API integration, parallax.

- Requests to and responses from 3 APIs.
- Node, jQuery, Moment, API integration.

- Gets user input, compares to friends objects stored in server, displays results.
- jQuery, Express, REST APIs.

• Write, update, save, clear notes.

Mongoose, Express, Cheerio.

EXPERIENCE

<u>Teaching Assistant</u> – *Trilogy Education* – Denver, CO

2019 - Present

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp at University of Denver. Lead Office Hours sessions. Manage student resource and activity distribution. Guide students through debugging and machine setup, version control, deployment troubleshooting in class and on Slack. Grade homework and projects.

Key Accomplishments:

- Proven firm grasp of Full Stack concepts and technologies.
- Demonstrated professionalism and effectiveness in leading and participating in group work.
- Learning on the spot by applying documentation research and Google techniques to bug handling and optimization efforts.

Technician I / III - Life Science Laboratories - East Syracuse, NY

2016 - 2018

Trained, supervised, delegated tasks to lower technicians. Recognized atypical data and applied judgement to interpretation. Improved existing scientific and reporting methods and developed new technical guides.

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted from Technician I to Technician III six months after hire.
- Identified weak spots in processes and formulated strategies to strengthen inter- and cross-departmental cohesiveness and efficiency.
- Increased revenue by performing analyses more efficiently than the standard rate and rapidly handling four months of backup.

<u>Supply Chain & Marketing Specialist</u> – Endra Life Sciences – Ann Arbor, MI

2015 - 2016

Maintained company website with MODX CMS. Developed promotional materials with Adobe Photoshop. Met weekly with product manager and lead build engineer. Worked directly with customers and vendors to determine technical and administrative needs.

Key Accomplishments:

- Increased sales by 120% over 2014 by identifying targets at top U.S. and foreign cancer centers.
- Traveled to international financial establishment with urgent business to complete sale to foreign medical institution.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO – Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp **University of Michigan**, Ann Arbor, MI – B.S. Neuroscience